<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Backend-as-a-Service on Geared to aid the geek</title>
    <link>https://hugo-theme-gruvbox.schnerring.net/tags/backend-as-a-service/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Backend-as-a-Service on Geared to aid the geek</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2021</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 16:26:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hugo-theme-gruvbox.schnerring.net/tags/backend-as-a-service/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Appwrite Firebase open source alternative is here</title>
      <link>https://hugo-theme-gruvbox.schnerring.net/blog/baas/appwrite-firebase-open-source-alternative/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 16:26:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo-theme-gruvbox.schnerring.net/blog/baas/appwrite-firebase-open-source-alternative/</guid>
      <description>Appwrite is a platform for building and deploying web and mobile applications more quickly and efficiently. Appwrite is an open-source Firebase alternative that provides services like authentication, authorization, storage, and database (No-SQL). Appwrite is designed to be flexible and scalable, you need to host it yourself, unlike Supabase which provides a managed host option.
Appwrite APIs# REST# Appwrite exposes a REST API that developers can use to access various functions and services on the Appwrite server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to Supabase: The Open-Source Alternative to Firebase</title>
      <link>https://hugo-theme-gruvbox.schnerring.net/blog/baas/supabase/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 10:26:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo-theme-gruvbox.schnerring.net/blog/baas/supabase/</guid>
      <description>What is Supabase?# Supabase is an open-source platform that provides Backend-as-a-Service (BaaS). Supabase provides SDK for platforms like web, and mobile (Android &amp;amp; IOS) that helps you speed up the development process and manage all the services you will need for the development.
Supabase is developed to help developers to set up their backends in minutes, living up to their slogan &amp;ldquo;Build in a weekend, scale to millions&amp;rdquo;.
Supabase vs Firebase# Supabase is marketed as &amp;ldquo;Supabase is an open-source Firebase alternative&amp;rdquo; let&amp;rsquo;s see how true it is.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
